<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>New Run Shenanigans</name>
    <directory>new run shenanigans</directory>
    <id>3257282571</id>
    <description>This mod requires REPENTOGON. Press the tilde key to open the new debug console and menu. There's a new Shenanigans option that will let you start a new randomized run.

[list]
    [*]Choose a difficulty (normal/hard/greed/greedier/random) or a random challenge
    [*]If you chose normal/hard/greed/greedier/random then you can select a random player type from regular, tainted, or both
    [*]Player types, difficulties, and challenges must be unlocked to be eligible for the randomization
    [*]You can disqualify player types, difficulties, or challenges from their respective tabs by deselecting them
    [*]You can also limit to player types with missing completion marks, or challenges that haven't been completed
    [*]Enter a seed if you want to play a seeded run
[/list]

Note: Challenges have a set player type and difficulty assigned to them, and are not allowed to be seeded.

Modded player types and challenges are supported. If they're hidden then they'll be deselected by default.

When you press tilde to open the menu, the game may put you into keyboard mode. There's a controller option you can set if you're trying to play with a controller.

Experimental support for the [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3148652146]Difficulty Library[/url] has been added. To use it:
[olist]
    [*]Navigate to the &quot;New Run&quot; menu
    [*]Select your difficulty (e.g. Insane from the Community Remix mod)
    [*]Open this mod's Shenanigans window and select &quot;Menu&quot; difficulty
    [*]Click &quot;Start New Run&quot;
[/olist]

From the &quot;New Run&quot; menu, the Difficulty Library can override this mod's difficulty selection. In order to use any other option besides &quot;Menu&quot; you'll be required to navigate to a different sub-menu (e.g. Challenges).

Update: There's a new option to choose a random recommended path for your run (in normal/hard mode). This path isn't forced. If you want forced paths then you can check out my [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2765647569]Randomness Challenge[/url] mod. In Rep, the option to go to Delirium involves RNG. In Rep+, the Delirium paths should always be available. The path will be displayed in the notification and in the Shenanigans window.</description>
    <version>1.23</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Player Characters"/>
    <tag id="Challenges"/>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
</metadata>
